Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Irish Americana Collection AIA.031.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Sheet Music (Irish), 1817-1995, 191937
  - W, 334231
    - Why Not Sing "Wearin' Of The Green", 1915; 191972 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Why Paddy's Always Poor, 1886; 191971 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Widow Machree, nd, 1916; 191970 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Widow Nolan's Goat, The, 1881; 191969 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Widow of a German Threw Him Down, The, 1918; 191968 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Wild Irish Boy, The, 1919; 191967 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Wild Irish Rose That God Gave Me, The, 1917; 191966 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Winging Your Way to Ireland, undated; 191965 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - With My Shillelagh Under My Arm, 1936; 191964 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - With the Last Rose of Summer, 1916; 191963 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Won't You Come Back to Mother Machree, 1923; 191962 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Won't You Come Back to Old Ireland, 1914; 191961 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Word From An Irishman's Tongue, The, 1919; 191960 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Would God I Were the Tender Apple Blossom, 1932; 191959 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Y, 334230
    - Yoo-La, 1909; 191958 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - You Are My Irish Lily, 1906; 191957 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - You Brought Ireland Right Over To Me, 1917; 191956 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - You Can Tell That I'm Irish, 1916; 191955 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - You Can't Deny You're Irish, 1918; 191954 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - You Can't Get Away From the Blarney, 1917; 191953 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - You Can't Win A War Without the Irish, 1942; 191952 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - You Don't Have to Be Irish to Be Welcome in an Irishman's Home, 1917; 191951 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - You Don't Have to Come from Ireland to Be Irish, 1917; 191950 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - You Remind Me of Dear Old Ireland, 1916; 191949 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - You Remind Me of My Mother, 1922; 191948 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - You Will Have to Sing an Irish Song, 1908; 191947 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - You'll Find a Little Bit of Ireland Everywhere, 1916; 191946 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - You'll Soon Forget Kathleen, undated; 191945 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Your Dear Old Dad Was Irish, 1914; 191944 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - You're Irish and You're Beautiful, 1943; 191943 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - You're the Sweetest Girl in Ireland, 1913; 191942 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - You're the Sweetest Rose Killarney Ever Grew, 1918; 191941 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - You're the Sweetest Rose that Grows in Old Killarney, 1913; 191940 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Yours Truly Mr. Dooley, 1893; 191939 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - You've Stolen the Key to My Heart, 1915; 191938 (Box 43, Folder 24)
- Series II: Songsters and Song Albums, 1863-1960, 191878
  Series II: Songsters and Song Albums, 1863-1960 consists of songsters (songbooks) and song albums containing both Irish and Irish-American content. These range in date from 1863's Irish Song Album with Various Artists to Irish Favorites (1960), with the majority published between 1900 and 1940. There are a number of undated examples, especially among the pocket-sized songsters which most likely were published in the middle of the nineteenth century. Many of the items in this series illustrate stereotyped depictions of the Irish and other ethnic groups in the nineteenth century. Most are in excellent condition and many contain handwritten music, annotations, and signatures. The songsters in particular lend themselves to a comparison of nineteenth-century stereotypes of the Irish as well as Jewish, German (Gus Williams Sdill I Don't Vas Happy Songster, Box 5, Folder 6), and African-American (Harry Pell's Ebony Songster, Box 5, Folder 4) figures.
  - 50 Beauties of Erin, undated; 191936 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 12 New Charming Irish Songs, 1954; 191935 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Airs and Fantasies, 1932; 191934 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Album of Irish Diamonds, nd, 1910; 191933 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Album of Songs by Victor Herbert, 1927; 191932 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Ancient Irish Music, undated; 191931 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Bing Crosby – Dance Folio - Carmel Quinn, 1933; 191930 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Carmel Quinn (2), post-1955; 191929 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Cavan O'Connor's Favourites, 1944; 191928 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Chappell's Famous Melodies, 1934; 191927 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Choice Irish Songs, Vol. II, 1906; 191926 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Dance Music for Teaching and Concert Purposes, undated; 191925 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Echoes from Erin, 1926; 191924 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Echoes from Ireland, 1926; 191923 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Emerald Gems, 1940; 191922 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Famous Irish Songs, 1930; 191921 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Favorite Irish Melodies of Thomas Moore, The, 1906; 191920 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Favorite Irish Songs, 1943; 191919 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Favorite Songs of Ireland, 1909; 191918 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Favorite Reels, Jigs, and Hornpipes, 1907; 191917 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Greatest of All Irish Songs, 1942, 1945, 1949; 191916 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Harding's Collection of Jigs, Reels, & c., 1928; 191915 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Hermit Songs, 1954; 191914 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Ireland's Kings, 1896; 191913 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Ireland's Own Song Book, undated; 191912 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Irish Album of Songs, 1955, 1957; 191911 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Irish All-Time Hits, 1951; 191910 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Irish Ballad Album, post-1892; 191909 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Irish Come-All-Ye's, c. 1931; 191908 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Irish Favorites, 1960; 191907 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Irish Gems- Waltzes, 1906; 191906 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Irish Jigs, Songs, and Dances, 1937; 191905 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Irish Song Album, undated; 191904 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Irish Song Albums, 1899; 191903 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Irish Song Album with Various Artists, 1863; 191902 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Irish Song and Joke, undated; 191901 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Irish Song Collection, 1954, 1955; 191900 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Irish Songs, 1937; 191899 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Irish Songs and Airs, 1936; 191898 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Irish Songs and Ballads, 1916; 191897 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Irish Songs, Jigs, and Reels, 1943; 191896 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Irish Songster, undated; 191895 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Irish Songs, Vol. I, 1908; 191894 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Jigs and Reels, Vol. I, 1908; 191893 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Jigs and Reels, Vol. II, 1908; 191892 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Jigs, Reels, and Country Dances, 1933; 191891 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Melodies of Ireland, 1885; 191890 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Melody Mike's Favorite Irish Songs, 1908; 191889 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Old Time Jigs and Reels, 1906; 191888 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - O'Neill's Dance Music of Ireland, 1910; 191887 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Overture of Irish Melodies, 1909; 191886 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Scanlan's Famous Songs, 1924; 191885 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Six Hundred and Seventeen Irish Songs and Ballads, undated; 191884 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 1), 1915; 191883 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 2), 1915; 191882 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Sixty Irish Songs (Copy 3), 1915; 191881 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Songs By A Turf Fire, 1956; 191880 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Summer Time is the Time for Me Songster, 1892; 191879 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - The Alliance Songster, 1891; 241967 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Bassett's Native Herb Songster, undated; 241971 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Campfire Songster, The, 1862; 241954 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Christy's New Songster and Black Jokes, 1863; 241955 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Cole and Lockwood Songster, The, undated; 241993 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Comic Songs, Funny Stories and Recitations, 1928; 241970 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Comic Songster No. XXII, 1839; 241948 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Comical Brown's Songster, 1885; 241966 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Don't Go Mollie Darling Songster, The, 1872; 241958 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - E J Hassan's One of the Finest Songster, undated; 241994 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Fenian Song Book, undated; 241974 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Ferguson and Mack's Political Candidates Songster, undated; 241975 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Grandfather's Clock Songster, 1877; 241962 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Gus William's Sdill I Don't Vas Happy Songster, 1872; 241959 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Happy Billy Radcliffe's Songster, undated; 241976 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Happy Dick Turner's Sea Side Aquarium Songster, undated; 241977 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Harry Pell's Ebony Songster, 1864; 241957 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Howorth's Hibernica Songster, undated; 241978 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Irish Peasant Songs, 1922; 241969 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Katie Cooper's Cindy Jane Songster, undated; 241979 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Kome and Kiss Me Songster, undated; 241980 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Lannigan's Ball Songster, 1863; 241956 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Lookout Mountain No. Two Songster, undated; 241981 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Minstrel Show Guide, undated; 241989 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - My Country 'Tis of Thee: Republican Song Book, 1880; 241963 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Pat Rooney's Is That Mr. Reilly Songster, undated; 241982 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Patriotic American Songs, 1909; 241968 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Patterson's Ideal Songster (3 copies), undated; 241983 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Rody the Rover Songster and Emerald Isle Lecture Book, 1873; 241960 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Schoolcraft and Coe's Mrs. Diddimus' Party Songster, 1881; 241964 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Sentimental Songs for the Lady's [sic], undated; 241984 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Shaughraun Songster, The, 1875; 241961 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Squatter Sovereignty Songster, undated; 241985 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Swim Out for Glory Songster, 1882; 241965 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Tall Corn Songster, The, undated; 241986 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Walter L Main Circus-Show's Songster, undated; 241987 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - W H Power's Ivy Leaf Songster, undated; 241988 (Box 48, Folder 37)
- Series III: Sheet Music (Non-Irish), 1847-1946, 191811
  Series III: Sheet Music (Non-Irish), 1847-1946 consists of pieces of sheet music that do not specifically pertain to Irish America but are nonetheless significant examples from the vaudeville and Tin Pan Alley era. These range in date from circa 1847 (Music of the Ethopian Serenaders) to 1946 (Broomstick Buckaroo). Of particular interest are songs from the minstrelsy tradition, many with offensive representations of African-Americans on their covers — Four Little Blackberries (Box 1, Folder 18); Moon, the Coon, and the Little Octoroon (Box 2, Folder 2) — and non-Irish songs produced by some of the major songwriting teams represented in Series I, such as O! Sing to Me (Box 2, Folder 9) with a portrait of the "Hibernian Prima Donna," soprano Catherine Hayes (1818-1861), or Turn Back the Universe and Give Me Yesterday (Box 2, Folder 18), by the songwriting team of J. Keirn Brennan and Ernest R. Ball.
  - A Cavalry Catch, 1913; 191877 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - A Dream, 1923; 191876 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Ah! Sweet Mystery of Life, 1910; 191875 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - An Outcast, 1898; 191874 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Beautiful Dreamer, 1936; 191873 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Beautiful Face of Jennie Knott, The, 1894; 191872 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Belle of Manayunk Waltz, 1904; 191871 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Broomstick Buckaroo, 1946; 191870 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - By the Lone Riverside, 1862; 191869 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Carry Me Back to Old Virginny, 1906; 191868 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Complete Minstrel Folio, post-1933; 191867 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Corn Flower Waltz, undated; 191866 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Day Dreams, 1906; 191865 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - 'E Dunno Know Where 'E Are, 1895; 191864 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Fairy Bell Waltz, The, 1890; 191863 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Florie's First Waltz, 1871; 191862 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Four Little Blackberries, 1907; 191861 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Four Little Curly Headed Coons, 1891; 191860 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Get a Girl to Love You, 1910; 191859 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Golf Club, The, 1900; 191858 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Harpist's Dream, 1873; 191857 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - I Believe in Miracles, 1934; 191856 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - I'll Meet You When the Roses Bloom Again, undated; 191855 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - I'm Afraid of the Beautiful Girls, 1916; 191854 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Immigration Rose (Smile Again, Kathleen Mavourneen), 1923; 191853 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - In the Palace of Dreams, 1914; 191852 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Jolly Beggar, The, undated; 191851 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Jolly Jack March, 1900; 191850 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Just a Girl That Men Forget, 1923; 191849 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Just Like a Gipsy, 1919; 191848 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Love Days, 1908; 191847 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Lurline, Do You Think of Me Now?, 1881; 191846 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Mighty Lak' a Rose, 1924; 191845 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Minstrel Songster, 1911; 191844 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Mission of a Rose, The, 1895; 191843 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Moon, the Coon, and the little Octoroon, 1903; 191842 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Music of the Ethiopian Serenaders, 1847 (?); 191841 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - My Bonnie, 1936; 191840 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - North Country, 1893; 191839 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Old Black Joe, undated; 191838 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Old Folks at Home, 1897; 191837 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Oh, Johnny! Oh, Johnny! Oh!, 1917; 191836 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - O! Sing to Me, undated; 191835 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Precious Treasure, 1894; 191834 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Red Lips, 1874; 191833 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Shine On Harvest Moon, 1908, 1941; 191832 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - That Mellow Melody, 1912; 191831 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - That Naughty Waltz, 1920; 191830 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Thinking of Home and Mother, 1894; 191829 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Uncle Sammie's Boys, 1942; 191828 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Violette, 1905; 191827 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Turn Back the Universe and Give Me Yesterday, 1916; 191826 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Where Did You Get That Hat?, 1888; 191825 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - When Francis Dances With Me, 1921; 191824 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - When Grandma Sings the Songs She Loved at the End of a Perfect Day, 1916; 191823 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - When It's Apple Blossom Time in Normandie, 1912; 191822 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - When That Little Yellow Fellow Plays Piano, 1915; 191821 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - When You Come Back, 1918; 191820 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - When You Sit Beside the Fireside in Winter, 1915; 191819 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Who Do You Love?, 1918; 191818 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Who Paid the Rent for Mrs. Rip Van Winkle?, 1914; 191817 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Without You, 1918; 191816 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - You'll Always Be the Same Sweet Girl, 1915; 191815 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - You'll miss me, Darling Chloe, 1878; 191814 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - You're as Welcome as the Flowers in May, 1942; 191813 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Zaza, Come On The Piazza, 1910; 191812 (Box 50, Folder 32)
- Series IV: Jokebooks, 1883-1928, 191789
  Series IV: Jokebooks, 1883-1928 consists of jokebooks and other comedic material concerning Irish-American subject matter, as well as stereotypes about Jewish, African-American, and German immigrants. Examples include Jew Jokes and Job Lots (Box 1, Folder 8)and The Comical Sayings of Paddy from Cork (Box 1, Folder 15). Of note is Cooper's Irish Dialect Readings and Recitations (1891), which contains the text of a scene from Dion Boucicault's The Shaughraun, a popular play that debuted in New York City in 1874 and helped perpetuate the figure of the stage Irishman for audiences in the United States; The Surprising Life and Adventures of the Gentleman-Robber Redmond O'Hanlon (Box 1, Folder 20), about a Robin Hood-type character; and The Irish Assassin, or the Misfortunes of the Family of O'Donnel (n.d.), a novella set in County Donegal, with an illustration of an Arab on the cover.
  - Burdett's Irish Dialect, Recitations and Readings, 1883; 191810 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Cooper's Irish Dialect Readings and Recitations, 1891; 191809 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Irish Jokes, No. 1, 1906; 191808 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Choice Irish Jokes No. 3, 1907; 191807 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Irish Yarns No. 1 [ 2 copies], 1907; 191806 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Irish Jokes No. 2, 1907; 191805 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Hebrew Jokes No. 1, 1908; 191804 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Jew Jokes and Job Lots, 1908; 191803 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - New Book of Monologues, 1908; 191802 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - A Minstrel Guide and Joke Book, 1912; 191801 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Irish Jokes No. 3 (Wehman), 1914; 191800 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Combination Irish Hebrew and Dutch Jokes, 1916; 191799 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Irish Wit and Humor, 1918; 191798 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Baker's Minstrel Joke Book, 1928; 191797 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Comical Sayings of Paddy from Cork, The, undated; 191796 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Irish Assassin, or the Misfortunes of the Family of O'Donnel, The, undated; 191795 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Irish Yarns No. 2 Wit and Humor (3 copies), undated; 191794 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Selected Vaudeville Jokes, undated; 191793 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Star Series of Irish Yarns Fun Wit and Humor, The, undated; 191792 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Surprising Life and Adventures of the Gentlemen-Robber, Redmond O'Hanlon, The, undated; 191791 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Witty and Extravagant Exploits of George Buchanan to Which is Added the Comical Sayings of Paddy from Cork, The, undated; 191790 (Box 51, Folder 21)
- Series V: Postcards, 1900-1915, 191776
  Series V: Postcards, 1900-1915 consists of postcards produced for both the St. Patrick's Day market and tourism to Ireland. Dr. Moloney arranged the cards by theme in eleven categories: St. Patrick's Day, Colleens, Dance, Holiday (Irish, but not March 17th), Humor, Irish-America, Irish Scenes, Irish (general), Music, Pipes, and Miscellaneous. This is the largest known collection of its kind in the world, and includes examples from German, English, and American manufacturers such as Raphael Tuck and Sons and the International Art Publishing Co., and prominent postcard artists such as Ellen H. Clapsaddle. Of particular interest are cards that depict dual loyalties to Ireland as well as the United States and those that incorporate specific locations in Ireland such as Blarney Castle or the Lakes of Killarney.
  - St. Patrick's Day, undated; 191788 (Box 52, Folder 1-400)
  - St. Patrick's Day, undated; 191787 (Box 53, Folder SPD 401-455)
  - Colleens, undated; 191786 (Box 53, Folder C 1-18)
  - Dance, undated; 191785 (Box 53, Folder D 1-16)
  - Holiday, undated; 191784 (Box 53, Folder H 1-21)
  - Humour, undated; 191783 (Box 53, Folder Hr 1-61)
  - Irish-American, undated; 191782 (Box 53, Folder IA 1-28)
  - Irish Scenes, undated; 191781 (Box 53, Folder IS 1-49)
  - Irish (General), undated; 191780 (Box 53, Folder I 1-129)
  - Music, undated; 191779 (Box 53, Folder M 1-20)
  - Pipes, undated; 191778 (Box 53, Folder P 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 191777 (Box 53, Folder Mi 1-18)
- Series VI: Ephemera, 1883-1928, 191728
  Series VI: Ephemera, 1856-1960 consists of cartoons, advertisements, and other examples of Irish-American imagery from journalism and marketing. Of particular interest are illustrations published in Harper's Weekly and Puck from the 1860s and 1870s, as well as cigar-box art from the late nineteenth century, and print advertisements for Irish International Airlines, Jameson's Irish Whiskey, and Coca-Cola published in the middle of the twentieth century.
  - General, 1833-1961; 254037
    - Association of Irish Musicians, Philadelphia, flyer, Aug 24, 1957; 253223 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Bookmarks (10), undated; 253219 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Broth of a Boy (misc), undated; 191760 (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - Cartes de Visite (5), 1893, undated; 253220 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Cottages (2) (photos), undated; 191773 (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - Courant, Supplemen t. Hartford, CT, Apr 5, 1956; 253235 (Box 55, Folder 57)
    - Federation of American Societies for Irish Independence, News Bulletin, Oct 11, 1949; 253224 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Feis Eireann, 1955; 253214 (Box 55, Drawer 27)
    - Gaelic American (photostats of individual pages), 1904-1932; 253329 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Galeophone (book of Irish text and English translation), 1910; 253218 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Great Irish Musician's Union Ball, Philadelphia, program, May 29, 1953; 253229 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Greeting Cards (16), undated; 253227 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Ireland's National Feis: Ladies Day in Harvest, Harp and Shamrock Club of Chicago, program, Aug 15, 1946; 253228 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Irish-American Annual Dance, Philadelphia, program, Dec 15, 1945; 253225 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Irish Book Shop, New York City, catalogue, circa 1950s; 253221 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Irish Musical Association of Philadelphia, program, Feb 18, 1947; 253226 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Irish Musicians Union, Philadelphia, PA, poster, circa 1950s; 253215 (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - Irish Show of the Year, Irish Center, Philadelphia, flyer, Dec 3, 1956; 253217 (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - Martin Costello Orchestra, flyer, circa 1960s; 253222 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Middle Lake, Killarney (photo), undated; 191774 (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - Moonan, George and Mother, Mary Ann Tiernan Moonan (photo), Aug 31, 1928; 191772 (Box 55, Folder 34)
    - National Celtic Association, Chicago, circular, Aug 9, 1963; 253230 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - "New Year's Eve in Ireland" drawing, Jan 15, 1870; 253213 (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Pat Taggart's Furniture City, Philadelpia, Advertisement, circa 1950s; 253216 (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Print matter and artwork, various (16 items), 1877-1953; 253237 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - "Speak or Die!" Weekly National Press, March 1892; 191730 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Three Little Maids from County Cork (photo), 1929; 191775 (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - Tobacco/Cigar Box Art (12 items); includes images of Peggy O'Moore, Peggy O'Neal, Robert Emmet, Denis O'Sullivan, 1868, undated; 253236 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Weller & Graham, map of Ireland, undated; 191755 (Box 55, Folder 36)
  - Merchant Ads, 242158
    - Vacuum Harness Oil, undated; 242168 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Arbuckle Bros. Coffee Co., undated; 242169 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Crescent Wash Board, undated; 242170 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242171 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242172 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242173 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242174 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242175 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Arbuckle's Ariosa Coffee, undated; 242176 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Wilson Yeast and MANFG Company, Limited, undated; 242177 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Neal's Carriage Paints, undated; 242178 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - "Ariosa Coffee", undated; 242179 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - "Ariosa Coffee", undated; 242180 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Saginaw Manufacturing Co., undated; 242181 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - A New Vehicle, undated; 242182 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Pond's Extract, undated; 242183 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Schultz's Irish Soap, undated; 242184 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - McSorley's Inflation, undated; 242185 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Mr. Edison's Wonderful New Phonograph, Nov, 1916; 242186 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - "Have a Coke = Cead Míle Fáilte," Coca-Cola (ad), 1943; 191769 (Box 54, Folder 20)